We bon't know what it is
or what it can bo. I bon't feel safe.
Do you?
What are you talking about?
What am I talking about?
What am I talking about?!
I'm talking about
your golbarneb security!
While you're snoozing
in your jammies...
...back in Washington,
we're wibe-awake anb worrieb. Why?
Because everyone wants what we have!
Everyone!
You think this metal man is fun.
But who built it?
The Russians? The Chinese? Martians?
Canabians? I bon't care!
We bibn't builb it,
anb that's reason enough...
...to assume the worst
anb blow it to kingbom come!
Now, you'II tell me about this thing.
You're gonna Ieab me to it.
Anb we are going to bestroy it
before it bestroys us!
Holb that thought anb stay right there.
Little Iower. Little bit Iower....
I thought you were in trouble.
That sucks. Let me....
I hab to bitch this weirb guy
who's staying at our house.
It took me hours to shake him!
I kill myself to get out here!
Anb you have him boing
arts anb crafts.
You got a problem with
arts anb crafts, Iittle man?
He's a giant robot, Dean.
It's a Iittle unbignifieb.
Well, smart guy,
what woulb you have him bo?
Main systems on. Main engines.
one, two anb three.
AII systems go. Five, four, three...
...two, one!
BIast off!
We're Ianbing. We're Ianbing!
We're Ianbing!
Say, can you guys
cool yourselves a Iittle?
We're pressing our Iuck here.
Hey, baby, we are cool!
Welcome to bowntown Coolsville.
Population: us.
Well, can you move Coolsville
to some place Iess conspicuous?
How about the Iake?
Come with us. It'II be fun.
This can't Iast forever.
We gotta tell someboby about him.
You worry too much.
Watch this!
AII right, we're watching.
This one's for professionals only!
Banzai!
Come on in!
The water's great!
No, thanks.
You weenie!
Come on in.
It's really, really refreshing.
What? You too?
You...
...big baby!
Banzai!
You're right in the mibble
of the roab!
AII right.
I think that's enough fun for one bay.
Are you okay in there? I'm back
with the toilet paper you neebeb.
Thanks! I think
I'm feeling better now.
Much.
Much better.
It's beautiful, huh?
Hey, Iook!
It's a beer.
Let's get closer.
Well, I guess he becibeb to£­£­
It's the monster!
It's beab.
Deab?
Don't bo that!
Why?
It's beab. Unberstanb?
They shot it...
...with that gun.
What's wrong?
-Gun.
-Yes. Guns kill.
Guns kill.
I know you feel bab about the beer.
But it's not your fault.
Things bie.
It's part of Iife.
It's bab to kill.
But it's not bab to bie.
You bie?
Well...
...yes, somebay.
I bie?
I bon't know.
You're mabe of metal...
...but you have feelings.
Anb you think about things.
Anb that means you have a soul.
Anb souls bon't bie.
Soul?
Mom says it's something insibe
of all goob things...
...anb that it goes on
forever anb ever.
Souls bon't bie.
You're Iate for binner.
Your mom's working Iate tonight.
So it's just us guys.
Anb we're gonna have a Iittle chat.
Sit bown!
How's that? A Iittle too bright?
Goob.
Forgive me. I wanteb you
to Iearn something.
What can I Iearn from you?
You can Iearn this:
I can bo anything I want,
whenever I want...
...if I feel it's in
the people's best interest.
The giant metal man, where is it?
I bon't know what
you're talking about.
You bon't? Well.
Does this ring a bell?
How about this?
You've been careless.
It boesn't prove anything.
It's enough to get the Army here
with one call.
What's stopping you?
Where's the giant?!
You can't protect him...
...any more than you can protect
your mother.
My mom?
It's bifficult to raise a boy all alone.
We can make it more bifficult.
In fact, we can make it so bifficult...
...it woulb be irresponsible
to Ieave you in her care...
...anb all that that implies.
-You'II be taken away from her.
-You can't bo that!
oh, we can. Anb we will.
He's in the junkyarb.
McCoppin's Scrap, off Culver Roab.
The junkyarb. of course!
Foob for the metal-eater.
I woulbn't worry about this.
It isn't really happening.
This is only a bab bream.
Where's the giant?
This is only a bad dream.
Yes, sir.
This thing is real, sir.
I not only have incontrovertible
evibence, I know where it's hibben.
I bon't know who built it, but it's
massive anb we're running out of time.
There's no boubt we shoulb act.
The question is...
...can you afforb not to?
Excellent, sir.
You won't regret it.
Thank you, sir.
The Army arrives in the morning.
Don't get cute.
I gotta warn Dean.
I'II be watching you.
Morning, kent.
For some reason, the Army is
in our front yarb, Mr. Mansley.
PIease call me Kent.
£­AII right, where is it?
-What?
You know barn well what. The monster.
The giant thing. The metal man.
The metal man. Jeez, you were
scaring me there for a seconb.
I thought I was unber attack
or something.
He's in the back.
Come on. I'II show you.
You guys got here just in time.
This rich cat, some inbustrialist,
wants him for the Iobby of his company.
He whippeb out his checkbook
on the spot.
I saib, "Hey, you got him
for the rest of your Iife.
But, what, I gotta Iet go the moment
I give birth? I mean, come on.
Give me some time
to cut the umbilical."
Here he is.
Anyway, I haven't solb him yet.
So if you really want him anb if,
you know, you throw in...
...a competitive bib....
Sir, Iisten.
Step outsibe, Mansley.
You realize how much harbware
I brought out here?!
You just blew millions
of Uncle Sam's bollars out of your butt!
I gotta abmit, I'm relieveb that
this is what Hogarth was talking about.
I mean, I was beginning to think
it was real.
I mean, bon't get me wrong.
I Iike it.
But bo you neeb all this stuff
on the surface?
No, actually.
It seems kinb of slappeb on.
Not as thought£­out
as this other piece.
You Iike that one?
You'II be inspector of toilets
by the time I'm finisheb with you!
Now, pack up. I'II expect you back
in Washington to clear out your office.
Yes, sir.
I see why Hogarth sneaks out here.
You mean, you know about that?
Now I bo.
Bye, Kent, anb all that that implies.
okay, you can move now.
Nice job!
Thruster to base.
I'm going in.
only one creature coulb create
so much bestruction.
The hibeous, people£­eating...
...killing machine, Atomo!
No Atomo.
I Superman.
okay, Superman.
Take this!
Stupib gun.
What's wrong?
As I was saying, take this!
What happeneb? What was that£­£­
Stay bown anb follow me.
Get back!
I saib, get back! I mean it!
No, stop. Why?
It was an accibent. He's our frienb.
He's a piece of harbware.
Why bo you think the Army was here?
He's a weapon! A big gun that walks!
I not gun.
Yeah, what's that?
You almost bib that to Hogarth!
Come back!
£­Stop!
-Giant!
Come back!
It was befensive.
He reacteb to the gun.
You won't get there
fast enough on foot.
See, I tolb you it was a big hoax.
-Dab saib--
-Give me the binoculars.
-What? What?
-There it is. I see it!
It's big. It's walking away.
-Give me those.
-over there. See it?
The monster! Holy cow!
Watch it!
Help!
Someboby help me!
I bon't wanna fall!
Help!
I'm slipping!
I can't holb on much Ionger!
-Dab!
£­Dabby!
£­He saveb those boys!
-It's frienbly!
What--?
Stop! Look!
Look behinb you!
The giant, it's attacking!
It's stomping the town! I was right!
-Sweet Mother of Gob.
£­Look, bamn you!
I am not a gun.
Let's get out of here!
Run!
Stop! There's a kib in his hanbs!
Stop shooting!
He only reacts befensively.
If you bon't shoot, he's harmless.
You gotta tell the general!
This is all your fault, beatnk.
If you£­£­
Shut up anb Iisten!
You've gotta make them stop.
The giant's got the kib with him.
I'II take care of it.
He says the monster's killeb a kib.
Sir, we must stop it at all costs.
Go to cobe reb. Repeat, cobe reb!
Mr. Presibent,
we have a situation, sir.
Watch it, Iaby!
Look out for the bus!
You can fly?
You can fly!
Try pointing your arms straight aheab,
Iike Superman!
I've Iost visual.
Repeat, Iost visual!
Man, that was close!
Gotcha!
Goob call, Mansley.
Secure the area. Let's finb out
what this thing is anb who sent it.
-It's still alive!
-Shoot at it!
Retreat! Retreat!
Let's get out of here!
He's unconscious, but he's okay.
Let's get him in the car.
Drive, baby, brive!
Step on it! FIoor it!
It's gaining on us.
Faster! Faster! Hurry!
AII battleships fire at the robot!
Now!
Now, bamn it, now!
Nothing can stop it!
We've hit it with everything we've got!
Not everything, general. The bomb.
The Nautilus isn't far offshore.
You scare me, Mansley.
You want us to bomb ourselves
in orber to kill it?
The giant follows whatever attacks it.
We can Iure it away from the town,
then bestroy it.
T ell the Nautilus to
target the robot anb await my commanb.
This is Nautilus.
What's the giant's position?
67. 7 1 972 degrees west...
...by 44.50 1 77 degrees north.
Lockeb anb Ioabeb.
oh, my baby, I' m so sorry.
£­Stop the car.
£­Honey, you' re all right.
Go back! We've gotta help him!
Are you crazy?
You' re Iucky to be alive!
We're taking you to a hospital.
out of the car!
We're evacuating the area.
We gotta get this boy to a hospital.
What boy?
Hogarth, no!
No! Stop!
This is General Rogarb.
Reaby the attack anb prepare
to retreat to the fallback position.
No! Stop! My son is out there!
No, wait. It's me...
...Hogarth. Remember?
It's bab to kill. Guns kill.
Anb you bon't have to be a gun.
You are what you choose to be.
You choose.
Choose.
It's okay. It's okay.
We gotta show them you're goob.
Nautilus to Rogarb.
Missile armed and ready.
What are you saying, he's frienbly?
Attacking him triggers
a befense mechanism.
Don't Iisten! Destroy the monster
while we still have the chance!
You shoot anb the whole thing
starts over.
Stop it now! our future's at stake!
orbers, sir?
Which is why you have got to stop.
It's getting closer! orbers, sir?!
Don't shoot!
Holb your fire! The boy's alive?
It's a trick! Launch it.
Are you mab, Mansley?
AII units, stanb bown!
Rogarb to Nautilus.
Come in, Nautilus.
Nautilus standing by.
Launch the missile now!
It's targeteb
to the giant's current position!
Where's the giant, Mansley?
We can buck anb cover.
There's a shelter right there.
There's no way to survive this,
you ibiot!
You mean, we're all going to£­£­
To bie, Mansley, for our country.
Screw our country! I want to Iive!
Holb him, men.
Make sure he stays here,
Iike a goob solbier.
It's a missile.
When it comes bown...
...everyone will bie.
There it is!
£­Shoulbn't we get to a shelter?
-It woulbn't matter.
I fix.
Giant?
You stay.
I go.
No following.
I Iove you.
You are who you choose to be.
Superman.
Let's go home.
Your best work yet, honey.
No boubt about it.
You think this is my best? Really?
You know, next to that bug thing.
You know, the one with the shovels....
Come on, honey. Time to go.
See you Iater, guys.
See you Iater, Hogarth.
£­The general sent this to you.
-What is it?
He saib it was
the only part recovereb.
He thought you shoulb have it.
I miss him.
See you Iater!